Robert S. Rohloff

Phone: 262-951-5300 Email: rohlofrs@gmail.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/robertrohloff/
GitHub: github.com/robrohlo

Professional Summary

Junior App and Web Developer able to build a web presence from the ground up utilizing well-designed, testable and efficient code in accordance with current best practices. Previous work experience includes scientific research and clinical research patient interaction. Consistently commended by instructors for the ability to quickly grasp new skills and technologies. Known as an imaginative problem solver always striving to learn and improve, with the social aptitude to fit into any team environment.

Skills

HTML/CSS • XML • Git • Java • JavaScript • AJAX • JQuery • Node.js • ReactJS • Angular • PHP • SQL • Android • iOS • Swift • Database Development • Agile Development Framework • Responsive Design

Education

Madison College

January 2017 – Graduation, December 2018

- Associate's Degree in IT Mobile Applications Development, GPA 3.9
- Honors Program Participant
- Member of Madison Information Technology Association

University of Wisconsin - Eau Claire

September 2007 – Graduation, May 2012

- Bachelor of Science Degree in Ecology and Environmental Biology
- Received the Gritzmacher Award for Biology
- Studied ecology and conservation efforts on site in Ecuador and the Galapagos Islands
- Member of The Singing Statesmen, an internationally recognized men's choral ensemble

Notable Projects

Quizki - Online Study Tool and Quiz Site

- Website used to design custom quizzes for studying, teaching, and trivia purposes
- Worked in Angular on frontend UI design and functionality/backend database functionality
- Created in collaboration with a small team from Meetup social organization website
- https://github.com/team-quizki/

Hewlett Packard Enterprises- Standards of Business Concepts Website

- Employed by marketing agency to translate English site into 26 different languages
- Used text editing functions within Wordpress to edit HTML content
- QA'd previously translated pages to ensure accuracy and functionality and reviewed feedback from client and fixed bugs and issues that arose during translation
- sbc.hpe.com

Mail Center Website Prototype

- Worked with the Mail Center Manager to design a proof-of-concept website prototype for potential implementation in the Madison College domain
- Platform designed to provide staff and facility access to services, links to resources

- Utilized HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Presented and demonstrated solution to Honors Program review board and relevant facility

Experience

ReactJS Developer

MedChain, Denver, CO

May 2019 - Present

- Working in Scrum team to develop dynamic website frontend using React Redux
- Troubleshooting inherited code to fix bugs and correct functionality
- Report directly to company CTO

Contract Developer

The Creative Group at Robert Half, Denver, CO

January 2019 - Present

- Burns Marketing, Denver, CO, 2/19 3/19
 - Hewlett Packard Enterprises- Standards of Business Concepts Website (detailed above)

Clinical Research Coordinator, Pediatrics

Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, WI

March 2016 – September 2016

- Responsible for providing updates and communicating with corporate study sponsors
- Directed the requisition, collection, labeling, storage, or shipment of specimens
- Informed patients or caregivers of study aspects and guided them through study logistics
- Performed tasks in accordance with study parameters such as interviewing subjects, taking vital signs, and performing ECGs

Clinical Research Assistant, Neurology

Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, WI

December 2013 – February 2016

- Developed and submitted protocols to Institutional Review Board
- Designed and implemented fMRI experiments and procedures
- Performed analysis on data sets for MEG and fMRI
- Catalogued data using statistical analysis programs, e.g. SPSS, Excel, REDCap

Clinical Research Coordinator, Pediatrics

Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, WI

September 2012 – September 2013

- Worked with supervisor to develop and articulate research plan incorporating requirements and navigating time, budget, and resource constraints
- Performed chart review to extract data and execute against research plan
- Trained interns on data extraction procedures and reviewed work to ensure consistency

Intern, Taxidermy and Zoology

Milwaukee Public Museum, Milwaukee, WI

December 2012 – September 2013

- Worked under museum taxidermist on avian and feline study skins for collection
- Assisted in sculpting of life-size horse mannequins
- Conducted behind the scenes tours for visitors with museum membership